Guide to the Viewbooks Collection, 1875 - [ongoing]
Viewbooks Collection, 1875 - [ongoing]
Special Collections & Archives, Wesleyan University
Wesleyan University (Middletown, Conn.)
1000-116
1.75
4
Wesleyan University viewbooks are brochures or booklets featuring photographs and information about the university. They are most often intended for prospective students, but may also be designed to attract donors.
The Viewbooks Collection contains items related to Wesleyan University from 1875 through 2006. They frequently include photographs and statistics from the time period.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Acquisitions Information
Gathered by staff of University Archives.
Historical Note
Wesleyan University viewbooks are brochures or booklets featuring photographs and information about the university. They are most often intended for prospective students, but may also be designed to attract donors.
Collection Overview
The Viewbooks Collection contains items related to Wesleyan University from 1893 through 2006. They frequently include photographs and statistics from the time period.
Online Catalog Headings
These and related materials may be found under the following headings in online catalogs.
Wesleyan University (Middletown, Conn.)--Students.; Wesleyan University (Middletown, Conn.)--History.; Wesleyan University (Middletown, Conn.)--Admission.; Advertising--Universities and colleges.; Viewbooks.
Related Material
Vertical Files on Admissions and the Admissions Department available in Special Collections & Archives, Wesleyan University.
Detailed Description of the Collection
  - Wesleyan University, circa 1875-1880 (Box 1, Folder 1a)
    2 page description of Wesleyan's curriculum, campus, Middletown, and expenses. For further information or for catalogues, apply to the President, Rev. Cyrus D. Foss, D.D., Middletown, Conn.
  - Snap Shots from Wesleyans [sic] Campus, 1893 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Includes photos with captions, but no other text. 2 copies.
  - Souvenir of Wesleyan University, published in the interests of the Athletic Associations of the College by the Wesleyan Argus, 1896 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Includes photos with captions, but no other text. 3 copies, two with a brown cover, one with a red cover.
  - A Circular of Information Concerning Wesleyan University, Middletown, Conn., 1899 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Issued by the faculty for the benefit of prospective students.
  - Wesleyan University: Her History and Her Needs, 1900 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Undergraduate Life at Wesleyan, circa 1901-1903 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    By Arthur Goodrich, managing editor of The World's Work.
  - Undergraduate Life at Wesleyan, circa 1905 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    By Arthur Goodrich.
  - Views of Wesleyan at Middletown, Conn., circa 1906-1907 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Cover title: Glimpses of Wesleyan.
    A booklet published for the purpose of presenting to friends of Wesleyan University a few glimpses of her campus and its beautiful surroundings. Published by Robert W. Rice [class of 1908] and John J. Norton [class of 1910]. Delta Kappa Epsilon House, Middletown, Conn.
  - A Talk with a Sub-Freshman by an Undergraduate of Wesleyan University, circa 1910 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    2 copies, slightly different layout and cover on each.
  - A Trip to Wesleyan, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Arranged for the Wesleyan Alumni Council, by K. M. Goode, [class of] 1904. 2 copies.
  - From such sources as this--, 1919-1920 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Written by Henry Merritt Wriston as part of the campaign to raise $3,000,000 for the university's endowment. 2 copies.
  - Connecticut and Wesleyan, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    3 copies.
  - A Trip to Wesleyan, circa 1920 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    2 copies.
  - A Trip to Wesleyan, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Edited by the Wesleyan University Alumni Council.
  - A Trip to Wesleyan, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - A Trip to Wesleyan, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Wesleyan's Next Century, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Wesleyan University, Middletown Connecticut, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Text with prints by Louis Orr.
  - Wesleyan University, circa 1931 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - A Student Description of College Life at Wesleyan, Written and Edited by Undergraduates, circa 1931-1932 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Text only.
  - Wesleyan University, circa 1935 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Wesleyan University: A Student Looks at Wesleyan, circa 1935 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Written and Edited by Undergraduates (Professor Snow's Course in Advanced Composition)
  - Wesleyan University, Middletown, Connecticut, 1936-1937 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Includes photographs, no text. 3 copies.
  - An Illustrated Description of Wesleyan University, Middletown, Connecticut, in Words and Pictures, 1936-1937 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Published by the University.
  - Wesleyan University, Midddletown Connecticut: Illustrated, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    A supplement to the Wesleyan University Alumnus, January 1937. 2 copies.
  - Wesleyan University, Middletown, Connecticut, in Words and Pictures, 1938-1939 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Wesleyan, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Also includes An Illustrated Description of Wesleyan University,
  - An Illustrated Description of Wesleyan University, January 1941 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Supplement to the Wesleyan University Alumnus, Volume XXV, Number 3. 2 copies, one of which has no printing on cover.
  - Wesleyan University postcard set, circa 1945 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Published by the College Store, Wesleyan University.
  - Wesleyan University: A College of Liberal Arts, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - The Veteran and Liberal Education, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Includes note stating that Wesleyan was only able to admit one-fifth of applicants in 1946, and that circumstances have forced the school to turn away strong applicants.
  - Wesleyan University: A College of Liberal Arts and Sciences, Middletown, Connecticut, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Still More Brightly... circa 1953 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    Published by the Development Program, Wesleyan University. 2 copies. One copy includes letter from John E. Kaltenbach, Executive Director of University Development.
  - Wesleyan University: A College of Liberal Arts and Sciences, circa 1956 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Wesleyan University: An Independent College of Liberal Arts and Sciences for Men, circa 1957-1958 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    Cover photograph of two students talking outside Foss Hill dormitories. White lettering on cover.
  - Wesleyan University: An Independent College of Liberal Arts and Sciences for Men, circa 1959-1960 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    Cover photograph of two students talking outside Foss Hill dormitories. White lettering on cover. 2 copies.
  - Wesleyan University: An Independent College of Liberal Arts and Sciences for Men, 1960-1961 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    Cover photograph of two students talking outside Foss Hill dormitories. Red lettering (Wesleyan) on cover. 2 copies.
  - Wesleyan University: An Independent College of Liberal Arts and Sciences for Men, 1961-1962 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    Cover photograph of two students talking outside Foss Hill dormitories. Red lettering (Wesleyan University)on cover. 2 copies.
  - Wesleyan University: An Independent College of Liberal Arts and Sciences for Men, 1962-1963 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    Cover photograph of College Row. 2 copies.
  - Wesleyan University: An Independent College of Liberal Arts and Sciences for Men, 1963-1964 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    Cover photograph of columns outside Olin Library. 2 copies.
  - Wesleyan University, 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    Cover photograph of contemplative student. 2 copies.
  - to every Wesleyan Alumnus.. ., 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    Plans for Wesleyan's Development Program. 2 copies.
  - to every Wesleyan Alumnus.. ., Fall 1965 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    Regarding sale of American Education Publications to Xerox.
  - Wesleyan University, 1965-1966 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    Cover includes photos of men talking outdoors, Olin Library, and a basketball player. 2 copies.
  - Wesleyan University, 1969-1970 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    Discusses introduction of coeduation and graduate education. 2 copies.
  - Wesleyan University Bulletin, September 1973 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    Volume LXVII, Number 3. Cover is series of red 'W's.
  - Wesleyan University Bulletin, 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Wesleyan University Bulletin, 1978-1979 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Wesleyan University, 1978-1979 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    Pamphlet.
  - Wesleyan University, 1979-1980 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Wesleyan University Bulletin, 1980-1981 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Wesleyan University, 1980-1981 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Wesleyan University Bulletin, 1981-1982 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Wesleyan University, 1982-1983 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Wesleyan University Bulletin, 1983-1984 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Wesleyan University Bulletin, 1984-1986 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Wesleyan University, 1985-1986 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Wesleyan University, 1986-1987 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    Red cover.
  - Wesleyan University, 1987-1988 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Wesleyan University, 1988-1989 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    Black cover.
  - Wesleyan University, 1989-1990 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Wesleyan University, 1990-1991 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Wesleyan University, 1991-1992 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Wesleyan University, 1993-1994 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Wesleyan University, 1994-1995 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Wesleyan University, 1995-1996 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    Oversize brochure that unfolds into a poster.
  - Wesleyan University, 1996-1997? (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Wesleyan University, 1996-1997 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    Trifold oversize brochure. Quote on cover: place in our community of learning. Wesleyan University
  - Wesleyan University circa 1997 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    Quote on cover: A Wesleyan education: critical and creative thinking that can change your life... and can help you chane the world.
  - Wesleyan University circa 1999 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    Quote on cover: 'Wesleyan is one of a handful of colleges that can stake a legitimate claim to the title tops in the nation.' -- The Fisk Guide to College, 1999.
  - Wesleyan University Prospectus, 2002-2003 Academic Year (Box 4, Folder 1)
    Multiple publications within portfolio.
  - Wesleyan University: Middletown, Connecticut, Founded in 1831, 2003 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    Unfolds into poster.
  - Wesleyan University: Middletown, Connecticut, Founded in 1831, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Wesleyan University Prospectus, 2005-2006 Academic Year (Box 4, Folder 2)
    Multiple publications within portfolio. 2 copies.